GRAHAM NESSLER

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

graham@grahamnessler.com 🚱 http://www.grahamnessler.com/ 📞 (215) 804-7381 (USA)

SUMMARY

I am a former history professor and <u>published author</u> turned software developer. I am most knowledgeable about React, Redux, jQuery, and JavaScript (ES6 and ES5), though I have worked with many other technologies, including newer tools such as React Native and Electron. I believe that the core purpose of technology is to improve people's lives, and I am continually pushing myself to learn new skills.

SKILLS

CORE TECHNICAL TOOLBOX: React.js, Redux, React Native, JavaScript/ES6, ExpressJS, jQuery, JSON, CSS/SASS, HTML5 Canvas, Ember, TDD, Websockets, HTML5, Firebase, Git/Github, Postgres and SQL, Webpack, Vim, Angular, Enzyme and Selenium, Mocha and Chai, Swift

ADDITIONAL TECHNOLOGIES: Sketch, Atom, Sublime Text, Microsoft Office, Blackboard, Turnitin

OTHER SKILLS: Agile, Web accessibility/ARIA, Excellent writing skills, Proficient in Spanish, French, and English, Working knowledge of Brazilian Portuguese, Mentoring and leadership, Teaching and public speaking, Teamwork and group collaboration

OPEN SOURCE CONTRIBUTIONS

Webdriver IO Add some clarifications to guide.md

Link

Debugpolitics.com Add hover color change for footer links and a readme

Link

Spell check for Atom text editor Revised readme for clarification

Link

Promise It Won't Hurt (Nodeschool course) Some small changes for clarity (to instructions)

Link

PROJECTS

FareHarbor Toolkit

This is a powerful tool creator for FareHarbor, an online travel services company, created with colleague Ryan Westlake. It consists of three tools--a search input tool, a footer tool, and a bottom modal tool--and a config setup that allows FareHarbor to easily customize these three and other tools for their clients' websites. The project was built to help increase conversions for FareHarbor's clients.

My core contributions: created the search input tool and footer tool; wrote documentation on these tools; co-created the config setup; co-authored intro section of documentation; created tests for my two tools.

JavaScript, ExpressJS, Selenium Webdriver, Sketch.

"Flash Shopper"

This is an independent solo project undertaken outside of the Turing School curriculum. It consists of a grocery list where users can enter in an item name, aisle, quantity, and a note. Users can also choose a category (such as "Bread") from a dropdown menu, which will then populate the aisle number (currently only for my local King Sooper's). The user can also sort items alphabetically and by aisle number and delete items.

React, Redux, Firebase, JavaScript, SASS/CSS, Webpack. See also my version in React Native.

(For other projects, please see my $\underline{portfolio}$).

EXPERIENCE

Florida Atlantic University

Visiting Professor of History · Aug 2015 to May 2016, Aug 2015 to May 2016 · Boca Raton, FL

Taught courses in United States, Caribbean, Latin American, and global history to around 200 students

Bentley University

Post-Doctoral Fellow · Sep 2013 to Jul 2015 · Waltham, MA

- Completed book manuscript
- Taught an undergraduate course on dictatorships in modern Latin America

Texas A&M University--Commerce

Ad Interim Assistant Professor of History · Aug 2012 to May 2013, Aug 2012 to May 2013 · Commerce, TX

Taught courses in United States and Latin American history at both the graduate and undergraduate levels

EDUCATION

Turing School of Software and Design

Certificate in Front End Engineering 2017

University of Michigan

PhD History 2011

College of William and Mary

BA History 2005